Charles S. Hyneman papers, 1920-1985 C2
Indiana University Archives
Charles S. Hyneman papers
1920-1985
Indiana University Archives
Hyneman, Charles S., 1900-1985
C2
10 cubic feet 10 boxes
Charles Hyneman was a Distinguished Professor of Political Science at Indiana University. Collection contains biographical materials, copies of articles, manuscripts, research notes, lectures, teaching materials, papers and reports relating to his work for the federal government during World War II, and general correspondence. Includes manuscript copies of American founding experience (published in 1994), Government and politics in the United States (not published), and some chapters of an unfinished book to have been co-authored by Hubert H. Humphrey on the American political system. Correspondents include Hubert H. Humphrey, Sander Vanocur, and Herman B Wells.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research. Advance notice is required.
Biographical Note
Charles S. Hyneman was born in 1900 on a farm in Gibson County, Indiana. He received the A.B. degree from Indiana University in 1923, and his A.M. in 1925. After pursuing graduate work at the University of Pennsylvania, he moved on to the University of Illinois, where he received his PhD in 1929.
Professor Hyneman taught political science at Syracuse University from 1928-1930 before returning to Illinois as assistant professor from 1930-37. In 1937 he became professor and chairman of the department of government at Louisiana State University. He became director of the new school of government and public affairs the following year, and was instrumental in organizing the Louisiana Municipal Association and initiating a merit system for the state civil service.
During World War II, Hyneman held three successive government posts. As administrative analyst in the Bureau of the Budget, he oversaw matters relating to the Office of Civil Defence. Later he worked in the Office of the Provost Marshall General in the War Department as Chief of the Training Branch, selecting ten universities to serve as centers for the training of civil affairs officers. Finally, he worked in the Federal Communications Commission, first as the Director of the Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service, and next as Assistant to the Chairman and then Executive Officer of the FCC.
In January 1947 Hyneman returned to teaching as professor and later chairman of the political science department of Northwestern University. At this time he also served as secretary of the Civil Service Board regulating employment in the Chicago Sanitary District. Hyneman joined the political science faculty at Indiana University in 1956, and in 1961 was named as a Distinguished Professor. He retired in 1970 with the title Distinguished Professor Emeritus of Political Science. Hyneman was a visiting professor at George Washington University, the University of Minnesota, Stanford University, UCLA, and the University of Washington. He served as President of the American Political Science Association from 1960-61.
He produced innumerable articles and many books: The First American Neutrality (1935), Bureaucracy in a Democracy (1950), The Study of Politics (1959), The Supreme Court on Trial (1963), A Second Federalist (1967), Popular Government in America (1968), Voting in Indiana (1979), American Political Writing During the Founding Era (1983), and The American Founding Experience (1994), the last published posthumously. He also left two sizeable unpublished manuscripts, Government and Politics in the United States, and many chapters of a book on the American political system to have been co-authored by Hubert H. Humphrey. Dr. Hyneman died in 1985.
Arrangement
Organized in five series: biographical materials; publications, manuscripts, and research notes; public lectures and teaching materials; government war work; and general correspondence.
Scope and Content Note
Charles Hyneman donated seven cubic feet containing his correspondence to the University Archives in 1982. After his death in January, 1985, another seven cubic feet comprising material of various kinds arrived at the archives. The collection relates to Hyneman's work as a member of the Indiana University faculty, and also contains material reflecting Hyneman's work at other universities and with the federal government before his arrival in Bloomington. The collection comprises ten cubic feet of records and dates from the 1920's to his death in 1985 and the posthumous publication of his final book in 1994, with the great majority of material covering the years after 1942.
Prominent types of materials in the collection include: correspondence, draft manuscripts, typed lectures, memoranda, reports, clippings, three reel-to-reel tapes and a gradebook.
Biographical Materials: This series includes 17 folders and three reel-to-reel tapes, arranged topically. Materials encompass the years 1937- 84, including transcripts of oral interviews (3 folders, 1976-79), contracts from universities (4 folders, 1937-62), Indiana University Annual Reports (1956-71), and other folders relating to a bibliography of his writings, a proposed endowment in his name, and others of a lighter nature.
Publications, Manuscripts and Research Notes: There are 51 folders in this series, chronologically arranged from his 1930's research notes to his handwritten musings on the sanctity of life. In addition to several articles are draft manuscripts of longer-term research products. Among these are manuscripts relating to the unpublished Government and Politics in the United States (6 folders), the unpublished book with Hubert H. Humphrey (23 folders), and drafts of what was published posthumously as The American Founding Experience (7 folders).
Public Lectures and Teaching Materials: The 36 folders and gradebook in this series date from 1935 to 1980, documenting a lifetime of talks given at conferences and universities across the country. The subjects of the talks range from the theory and practice of democratic government to the politics of race and protest to the concepts of the Founding Fathers. These have been filed chronologically, along with the materials relating to teaching (Teaching--Handouts and Notes-- 1935-69, Hyneman Circulars Regarding the Teaching of Political Science--1952-54, and the Gradebook, 1947-55.) Also related to teaching is the unpublished Government and Politics in the United States in Series 2, which grew out of his teaching at Northwestern University. There are no regular class lectures.
Government War Work: This series documents Dr. Hyneman's work in three government positions during the American years in World War II. Included within these 14 folders dating from 1942 to 1949 are materials from the Bureau of the Budget (2 folders), the Training Branch of the War Department (2 folders), and his work with the Federal Communications Commission (9 folders).
General Correspondence: The 201 folders included here were carefully kept by Dr. Hyneman, and comprise over half of the collection. Personal and professional correspondence is largely indistinguishable here, as the professor's professional colleagues and former students were frequently his closest friends. Material here are filed alphabetically, with organizations interfiled with individual names. More information regarding his publications may be found here, with critical correspondence of his work filed under the name of the press or under a book title. Correspondents include: William F. Buckley, Jr., Hubert H. Humphrey, Sander Vanocur, and Herman Wells.
Separated Material
Four cubic feet of materials were removed from the Hyneman collection. These included duplicate copies of conference talks, extra transcript copies of his oral history, duplicate draft chapters of a proposed book with Hubert H. Humphrey, and extra draft copies of a book which was posthumously published as The American Founding Experience. Additionally, typed and handwritten notes, much of it copied from state statutes, was removed, as were newspaper and magazine clippings. Two microfilm copies of The Ass, or the Serpent, printed in London in 1712, were transferred to the Main Library.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Lilly Library; Accession 93/018.
Political science --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington --History --20th century --Sources.; Political scientists --Indiana --Bloomington --Archives.; Political scientists --Indiana --Bloomington --Correspondence.; World War, 1939-1945 --War work.; Hyneman, Charles S., 1900-1985 -- Archives; Hyneman, Charles S., 1900-1985 -- Correspondence; Hyneman, Charles S., 1900-1985 -- Government and politics in the United States; Hyneman, Charles S., 1900-1985 -- American founding experience; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978 -- Correspondence; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978 -- Correspondence -- Selections; Vanocur, Sander -- Correspondence; Vanocur, Sander -- Correspondence -- Selections; Wells, Herman B -- Correspondence; Wells, Herman B -- Correspondence -- Selections
- Biographical Materials, 1925-1984
  - Annual Report, 1956-1971 (Box 1)
  - Bibliography for APSA, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Biographical--Misc., 1932-1983 (Box 1)
  - Biography; Publicity, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Birthday Parties, 1955-1970; 1980 (Box 1)
  - Employment (Box 1)
    - Indiana University, 1956-1962 (Box 1)
    - Louisiana State University, 1937-1978 (Box 1)
    - Northwestern University, 1946-1954 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Government, 1942-1947 (Box 1)
  - Hyneman Endowment, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1925-1974 (Box 1)
  - Oral History (Box 1)
    - Complete, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
    - 3rd Interview, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
    - 4th Interview, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Personal; Misc., 1937-1982 (Box 1)
  - Reel-to-reel tape--70th Birthday Party--Chicago, 1970; (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Reel-to-reel tape--Social Studies Conference, April 13, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Trivia & Frivolity, 1942-1980 (Box 1)
- Publications, Manuscripts and Research Notes, 1930-1994
  - Hyneman: Notes on Research, 1930's (Box 1)
  - New York Public Services Commission, 1930's (Box 1)
  - Early Tenure and Turnover Study: 1925-1935, 1935-1939 (Box 1)
  - American State Legislators, 1938-1941 (Box 1)
  - C.S. Hyneman--Research Projects, 1947-1965 (Box 1)
  - Government and Politics in the United States (Box 1)
    - Chapters 1-7, 1954; (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Chapters 9-12, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Chapter 13, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Chapters 17-20, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Chapters 21-23,37, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Legislators, Constituencies, and Political Behavior, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Iowa Legislature: A General Description, 1955-1959 (Box 2)
  - Indiana Politics--Research, 1956-1967 (Box 2)
  - Collection and Uses of Political Data, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Humphrey/Hyneman Book (Box 2)
    - Plans, 1962-1969 (Box 2)
    - Design of the Book, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Summary, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Notes Used, 1962-1971 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    - Original Type--Chapters 1-5, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Corrected MSS--Chapters 1-5, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Original Type--Chapters 6-9, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 1--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 2--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 3--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 4--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 5--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 6--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 7--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 8--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter 9--Final, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - H & H--Chapters 1-3, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - H & H--Chapters 4-7, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - H & H--Chapters 8-9, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Bibliography, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - HHH--Quotes, 1949-1972 (Box 2)
    - HHH Book--Discarded MSS, 1962-1974 (Box 2)
    - Chapter IV--"The Indiana General Assembly", 1960's (Box 2)
  - Distributed Self-government, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Voting in Indiana--Rejected Concluding Chapter, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Case for Revising the Constitution, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Draft of Book with Donald Lutz for AEI, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Ideological Foundations of Republican Government, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Materials copied for American Political Writing During the Founding Era, 1983 (Box 2)
  - American Founding Experience (Box 2)
    - Handwritten draft, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Typed draft of American Founding Experience, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Draft copies 1 & 2, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Draft copy 3, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Draft excerpts, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Most complete copy, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Appendices, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Sanctity of Life, undated (Box 3)
- Public Lectures and Teaching Materials, 1935-1980
  - Teaching--Handouts and Notes, 1935-1969 (Box 3)
  - Government for the Common Good, 1939 (Box 3)
  - On Instructional Provision for Political Leadership, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Gradebook, 1947-1955 (Box 3)
  - Hyneman Circulars Regarding the Teaching of Political Science, 1952-1954 (Box 3)
  - Lectures, 1952-1956 (Box 3)
  - Administration in Theory of Democratic Government, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Motivation, Incentives, & Achieving Agency Objectives, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Guide to Study of Democratic Government, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Lectures, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Governmental Restraint of Expression, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Theory of Democratic Government, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Policing the Democratic Process, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Some Critical Learning Experiences: A Personal View, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Politics of Race, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Lectures, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - American Democratic Way of Government, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Lectures, 1964-1967 (Box 3)
  - Political Theory--4 conferences, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
  - Lectures, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Political Obligation, Claims of Conscience, Resistance of Government..., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Whose University Is It?, March 1969 (Box 3)
  - Perspectives on Politics of Race, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Contemporary Protest and Resistance, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Lectures, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Elections, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Myth, Tradition, and Government by the People, 1974 (Box 3)
  - LSU Lectures, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Founding Fathers: Concepts and Achievements, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Responsibility of Administrative Organizations, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Continuing Electoral Reform: To What Ends, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Voting in Indiana: A Century of Persistence and Change, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Call for a Constitutional Convention: Why Not Have It Out Now?, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Federalism, State Constitutions, and the Establishment of Justice, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Agenda for Democrats: Challenge for Theory, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Iowa Lectures I to IV, undated (Box 3)
  - Iowa Lectures V to VIII, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, undated (Box 3)
- Government War Work, 1942-1949
  - Military Government General, 1943-1946 (Box 3)
  - Budget Bureau (Box 3)
    - Office of Civilian Defence Reports, 1942 (Box 3)
    - Reports General, April 1942-January 1943 (Box 3)
  - War Department (Box 3)
    - Chief of Military Government Training Branch, 1943-1944 (Box 3)
    - Training Branch--Files, 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - FCC Memos--Foreign Broadcasting Intelligence Service, 1944-1945 (Box 3)
  - FBIS Director--Papers (Box 3)
    - February 1945 (Box 3)
    - March 1945 (Box 3)
    - April 1945 (Box 3)
    - May 1945 (Box 3)
  - FCC Reading File (Box 3)
    - August 1945-March 1946 (Box 3)
    - April 1946-September 1946 (Box 3)
    - September 1946-December 1946 (Box 3)
    - Misc., 1946-1949 (Box 3)
- General Correspondence
  - A-Am, undated (Box 4)
  - ASCS Farm Committee (Box 4)
    - System--Study Committee--Correspondence, undated (Box 4)
    - Study--Hyneman's Memos, undated (Box 4)
    - Study--Hyneman's Draft of Report, undated (Box 4)
  - Allen, Joel, undated (Box 4)
  - Am-Az, undated (Box 4)
  - American Enterprise Institute (Box 4)
    - Bicentennial Plans, undated (Box 4)
    - General, undated (Box 4)
  - American Political Science Association, 1944-1967; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - American Spectator, undated (Box 4)
  - Appleton-Century-Croft, undated (Box 4)
  - The Supreme Court on Trial (Box 4)
    - Atherton Press Re:, undated (Box 4)
    - Criticism of Manuscript, undated (Box 4)
    - Letters re the Book, undated (Box 4)
  - Popular Government in America (Box 4)
    - Atherton Press Re:, undated (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and Reviews, undated (Box 4)
  - Ba, undated (Box 4)
  - Be, undated (Box 4)
  - Beckett, Paul, undated (Box 4)
  - Bi-Bo, undated (Box 4)
  - Blair, George S., undated (Box 4)
  - Blanksten, George I., undated (Box 4)
  - Boyd, Richard, undated (Box 4)
  - Bridge, Franklin, undated (Box 4)
  - Br-Bz, undated (Box 4)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., undated (Box 4)
  - Buehrig, Edward, undated (Box 4)
  - Bureaucracy in a Democracy (Box 4)
    - Correspondence re the Manuscript, undated (Box 4)
    - Reviews, Comments, undated (Box 4)
  - Buzzaird, Raleigh, undated (Box 4)
  - Ca-Ch, undated (Box 4)
  - Carey, George W. I, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Carter, undated (Box 5)
  - Christoph, undated (Box 5)
  - Ci-Cl, undated (Box 5)
  - Co-Con, undated (Box 5)
  - CED (Committee for Economic Development), undated (Box 5)
  - Coo-Cz, undated (Box 5)
  - Cooke, Edward F., undated (Box 5)
  - Da, undated (Box 5)
  - Dahl, undated (Box 5)
  - Dahl-Kirkpatrick, 1967 (Box 5)
    General
    "Dahl's investigation of CIA's intrusion into Political Science."
    - (Folder 1) (Box 5)
    - (Folder 2) (Box 5)
  - Day, William, undated (Box 5)
  - De, undated (Box 5)
  - Derge, undated (Box 5)
  - Declerico, Robert, undated (Box 5)
  - Di-Dz, undated (Box 5)
  - Driscoll, Jean, undated (Box 5)
  - Earhart Foundation, undated (Box 5)
  - E-Em, undated (Box 5)
  - Em-Ez, undated (Box 5)
  - Fa-Fi, undated (Box 5)
  - Fj-Fz, undated (Box 5)
  - Ga-Gn, undated (Box 5)
  - Gilbert, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Go, undated (Box 6)
  - Gra-Gre, undated (Box 6)
  - Graham, George J., Jr., undated; (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Gri-Grz, undated (Box 6)
  - Gs-Gz, undated (Box 6)
  - Ha, undated (Box 6)
  - Hagan, Charles, undated (Box 6)
  - Harper & Bros. (Box 6)
    - 1945-1949 (Box 6)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 6)
    - Harper & Row, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Havrylak, Sether, undated (Box 6)
  - He-Hi, undated (Box 6)
  - Heilman, Robert B., undated (Box 6)
  - Herson, Lawrence, undated (Box 6)
  - Ho-Hol, undated (Box 6)
  - Hofstetter, Richard, undated (Box 6)
  - Holden, Mathew, undated (Box 6)
  - Hom-Hoz, undated (Box 6)
  - Homer, Fred, undated (Box 6)
  - Hu-Huz, undated (Box 6)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. (Box 6)
    - Personal, undated (Box 6)
    - Campaign, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 6)
    - Kirkpatrick--Honorary Degrees, undated (Box 6)
  - I, undated (Box 6)
  - University of Illinois--University of Illinois Press, undated (Box 6)
  - Indiana University (Box 7)
    - General, undated (Box 7)
    - Bicentennial Lectures, undated (Box 7)
    - Memos, Committees, etc., undated (Box 7)
    - Political Science Department, undated (Box 7)
    - Press, undated (Box 7)
  - Info-Indiana Forum, undated (Box 7)
  - J, undated (Box 7)
  - Jacobson-West-Szmurak, undated (Box 7)
  - Janda, Kenneth, undated (Box 7)
  - Ka, undated (Box 7)
  - Ke, undated (Box 7)
  - Keefe, undated (Box 7)
  - Kendall, Willmoore (Box 7)
    - 1937-1948, (photocopies) (Box 7)
    - 1948-1960, (photocopies) (Box 7)
    - 1960-1969, (photocopies) (Box 7)
  - Ki-Ky, undated (Box 7)
  - Kirkpatrick, E.M., undated (Box 7)
  - Kneier, Charles M., undated (Box 7)
  - La, undated (Box 7)
  - Le, undated (Box 7)
  - Leege, David, undated (Box 7)
  - Legislative Tenure Survey Letters, 1930's (Box 7)
  - Leland, Simeon E., undated (Box 7)
  - Lence, Ross, undated; (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Li-Ly, undated (Box 7)
  - Liberty Fund, undated (Box 7)
  - Liberty Press/Classics--Correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Louisiana State University (Box 7)
    - Bureau of Government Research Council, undated (Box 7)
    - Scandals, Crime, Reform, undated (Box 7)
  - Lutz, Donald S., undated; (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Ma, undated (Box 8)
  - McCall, undated (Box 8)
  - Malone, undated (Box 8)
  - Mac and Mc, undated (Box 8)
  - McClure, Robert, undated (Box 8)
  - Me-Mi, undated (Box 8)
  - Mo-Mz, undated (Box 8)
  - N, undated (Box 8)
  - NRC (National Research Council), undated (Box 8)
  - National Science Foundation, undated (Box 8)
  - Northwestern University (Box 8)
    - General, undated (Box 8)
    - Political Science Department, undated (Box 8)
    - Curriculum, undated; (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - O, undated (Box 8)
  - O'Connor, Patrick, undated (Box 8)
  - O'Lessker, Karl, undated (Box 8)
  - Owen, James Kimbrough, undated (Box 8)
  - Pa-Pi, undated (Box 8)
  - Penniman, Howard, undated (Box 8)
  - Penniman-Ranney, undated (Box 8)
  - Pennsylvania State University Education Study, undated (Box 8)
  - Peters, Ron, undated (Box 8)
  - Pl-Pz, undated (Box 8)
  - Prentice-Hall, undated (Box 8)
  - Publishers--Misc., undated (Box 8)
  - Ra-Re, undated (Box 9)
  - Ranney, Austin, undated (Box 9)
  - Relm Foundation, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Ri, undated (Box 9)
  - Roa-Rol, undated (Box 9)
  - Robinson, James A., undated (Box 9)
  - Rom-Rz, undated (Box 9)
  - Sa-Se, undated (Box 9)
  - Scope & Method of Political Science Exploratory Conference, undated (Box 9)
  - Sh-Si, undated (Box 9)
  - Sm-So, undated (Box 9)
  - Smiley, undated (Box 9)
  - Snyder, R.C., undated (Box 9)
  - Social Science Research Council, undated (Box 9)
  - Sp, undated (Box 9)
  - Speckhard, Roy, undated (Box 9)
  - Sta-Ste, undated (Box 9)
  - Sti-Sty, undated (Box 9)
  - Stoke, Harold W., undated; (5 folders) (Box 9)
  - Stone, Ivan and Janice, undated (Box 9)
  - Stoner, undated (Box 9)
  - Students (Personal Data), undated (Box 9)
  - Study of Politics--Correspondents and Reviews, undated (Box 9)
  - Sm-Sz, undated (Box 9)
  - Ta-Te, undated (Box 9)
  - Th, undated (Box 10)
  - Ti-Tz, undated (Box 10)
  - U-V, undated (Box 10)
  - U.S. News & World Report--CSH on U.S. Supreme Court, 1965 (Box 10)
  - University of Dallas, undated (Box 10)
  - Van Dyke, Vernon, undated (Box 10)
  - Vanocur, Sander, undated (Box 10)
  - Vatikiotis, undated (Box 10)
  - Voting in Indiana--Reviews & Notices--Hofstetter and O'Connor Correspondence, undated (Box 10)
  - Wa, undated (Box 10)
  - Watts, Thomas, undated (Box 10)
  - We-Wh, undated (Box 10)
  - Wells, Henry, undated (Box 10)
  - Wells, Herman (Box 10)
    - Memorial (Box 10)
  - Wi, undated (Box 10)
  - Willis, undated (Box 10)
  - Wo-Wz, undated (Box 10)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, undated (Box 10)
  - Y-Z, undated (Box 10)
  - Young, Roland, undated (Box 10)
  - Misc. Correspondence, undated (Box 10)
  - Current Misc., undated (Box 10)